Mohammad El Prince

Mississauga, ON | 519-760-1559 | mohammad-elprince@proton.me LinkedIn | Github | Portfolio

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Full Stack Software Engineer with experience in JavaScript and Python-based programming. With a background in mechanical engineering and operations, I have a can-do attitude and bring strong skills in problem-solving, communication, and collaboration. I have a clear vision for leveraging technology to solve complex challenges and create meaningful impact. As a lifelong learner, I am committed to growing my technical knowledge and leadership skills. I enjoy tackling challenges head-on and crafting creative solutions to real-world problems. My belief in the power of teamwork through the Agile methodology guides me in achieving exceptional results.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, React.js, Next.js, FastAPI, Scss, SQL, VSCode, Git

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

WriteWell - GitHub | Demo | Live

WriteWell is a full-stack app that enables bloggers to share, edit, and delete blogs.

- Built with Next.js end-to-end and styled with Scss.
- Employed Next.is routing ability to construct endpoints for API requests.
- Utilized MySQL as the database, which is deployed on AWS RDS.
- Deployed images to AWS S3 and linked them to the database.

Portfolio - GitHub | Demo | Live

A high-quality digital showcase of my professional journey, highlighting my skills and projects.

- Employed HTML, CSS, and JavaScript showcasing my abilities to learn and in front-end web development and design.
- Incorporated interactive elements and animation using JS and CSS
- Maintained DRY coding following best practices in all the project files

GPT-3 Intro - GitHub | Demo | Live

A landing page created to describe GPT-3 technology that provides a brief introduction about this modern AI technology.

- Built with ReactJS and CSS styling showcasing an appealing user experience.
- Incorporated BEM (Block Element Modifier) technique to relate JSX elements to styling and for consistency.
- Deployed JSON server as the backend server.

Budget Tracker CLI - GitHub | Demo

A command-line application designed to help you manage your finances and track your expenses easily.

- Coded python scripts and functions and maintained DRY coding
- Imported SQLAlchemy for database management.
- Implemented the rich library for a user-friendly CL interface.

RECENT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Amazon, Hamilton/St. Thomas/London/Mississauga, ON Lead Fulfillment Associate/Field Quality Assurance

05/2021 - Present

- Manage 50+ Associates across Amazon Robotics (AR) floor and inventory workstations. Monitor the health of four Amazon Robotics floors for optimal productivity and safe operation.
- Guide Associate for an optimized performance resulting in 10% improvement in the AR floor health
- Train Level1 Leads and provide coverage for other managers.

University of Guelph, Guelph, ON

Teaching/Research Assistant

01/2019 - 05/2021

- Lectured large groups of students (75 150 students) on fundamental engineering courses and proctored exams.
- Conducted experimental and theoretical research in the areas of gas wells and safety of nuclear power plants.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School 02/2023 - 10/2023 Full Stack Web Development, Python and JavaScript online program

01/2019 - 02/2021

University of Guelph, Guelph, ON Master of Engineering — Mechanical Engineering (course-based)

King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals, Dhahran, KSA

Master of Science — Mechanical Engineering (Thesis-based) 09/2016 - 12/2018

Bachelor of Science — Mechanical Engineering (course-based) 01/2012 - 05/2016